因为每次我看见你的脸
'Cause every time I see your face
就情不自禁地失态
I can't help but fall from grace
这女的很棒
This girl's good.
是啊  歌词押韵  我以前倒没想过
Yeah, a song with rhyming words! I never thought of that before.
我喜欢她
I like her.
为什么  因为她会唱歌  会弹吉他
Why? Because she can sing and play guitar
还会边弹边唱吗
and do both at the same time?
这正是我对表演艺人的期待
That's pretty much all I'm looking for from these people.
看  你忌妒得要命
Look at you, all jealous.
菲比  拜托  你们俩的风格完全不同
Pheebs. Come on, you two have completely different styles.
她比较...  那个
You know, she's more.... You know?
而你比较...
And you're more....
说你会留在我身边
Say you'll stay beside me.
看到没  她唱完了大家都很开心
See? Everybody else is happy she's done.
我接下来要唱的是
Okay, my next song's called:
菲比·布菲  我该怎么说  我很怀念当初
Phoebe Buffay, What Can I Say? I Really Loved When We Were...
一起唱歌的日子  我不该那样离开你的
Singing Partners and I Shouldn't Have Left You That Way.
不是吧  唱这种别有深意的歌
No. One of those "look for the hidden meaning" songs.
嘿  菲比
Hey, Phoebe.
嘿  莱丝莉
Hey, Leslie.
你怎么知道我会在这里
How'd you know I'd be here?
我在卖大鱼的地方碰到弗拉德
I ran into Vlad at the place where they sell the big fish.
他说你常在这里表演  所以...
He said you played here a lot, so....
我要上洗手间
All right, listen, I have to go to the bathroom.
如果她们又谈到"大鱼"
But the place with "big-fish" comes up again...
我想知道是好几条大鱼
I'd like to know whether that's several big fish
还是只有一条大鱼
or just one big fish.
菲比说你写广告歌
So Phoebe tells us you write jingles.
我是说她抛弃我去写广告歌
Actually, I said she abandoned me to write jingles.
-有没有我们听过的  -当然有
- Anything we might've heard of? - Yeah!
家永远不远
Home is never far away.
回家的感觉就是家星炖品
Home is Homestar Stew.
但我已经不写了  我有点厌倦了
But I don't do that anymore. I got kind of sick of it.
我也写不出好东西了  所以被炒鱿鱼了
And then I couldn't come up with anything good, so they fired me.
太可惜了
Bummer.
你知道  我只是...
Well, you know, I was just....
我只是想  只是希望
I was just thinking and just hoping that...
也许你愿意跟我再度合作
maybe you'd want to get back together?
不了  谢谢你
No, but, thanks.
拜托  菲比  你考虑一下好吗
Come on, Phoebe. Would you just think about it?
好吧  不了  谢谢你
Okay. No, but, thanks.
好吧  再见  菲比
Okay, see you, Pheebs.
你好狠心
That was kind of brutal.
你们都要记住这个教训
Well okay, let this be a lesson to all of you, all right?
一旦背叛我  我就成了冷血的女人
Once you betray me, I become like the Ice Woman.
我是铁石心肠  绝不心软
I'm just very cold, hard, unyielding.
任何东西都无法穿透我这冰冷的外衣
You know, nothing can penetrate this icy exterior.
给我一张纸巾好吗
Can I have a tissue please?
里面有人吗
Is someone in there?
没人  我是在玩比大胆的游戏
No. This is just part of a dare devil game that I play
叫做"等到尿崩而死的前一刻"
called "Wait Until the Last Moment Before I Burst and Die."
老天  你掉厕所里去了吗  你好
Jeez, man! Did you fall? Hi!
你...  你是兴奋过度吗
So did you? Did you fall high?
女厕所有人  我等不及了
Someone was in the ladies' room. I couldn't wait.
不过我帮你把马桶盖掀起来了
I left the lid up for you, though.
这样吧  甘瑟  你先
You know what, Gunther? Go ahead.
我要跟这位
I'm talking to....
这时候你要报上你的名字
This is the part where you say your name.
金吉儿
Ginger.
金吉儿  我要跟金吉儿说话  所以...
Ginger. I'm talking to Ginger, so...
你不是要上厕所吗
Don't you have to use the bathroom?
不  不用
No, no.
我只是  我宁可跟你聊天
I just I'd rather talk to you.
是  我要上厕所
Yes, I do.
对  我再不上就不行了
Yes, I do have to go to the bathroom.
里面有人
Someone in here.
-钱德勒呢  -他去不了
- Where's Chandler? - He can't make it.
他说他要回去上班...
He said he had to go back to his job and do...
天哪
Whoa-oh!
乔伊
Joey?
乔伊·崔比安尼
Joey Tribbiani?
乔伊  我看得到你  好吗
Joey, I can see you, okay?
你藏在外套后面
You're hiding behind the coats.
差点就被逮到了
Close one.
嗨  亲爱的
Hi, sweetie.
嘿  罗斯
Hey, Ross.
嗯
Yeah, huh.
-我有个坏消息  -怎么了
- I've got some bad news. - What?
我可以去吃饭  但饭后要回来加班
I can get a quick bite to eat, but then I have to come back up here.
拜托  亲爱的
Come on, sweety.
你已经连续加班两星期了
You've had to worked late every night for the past two weeks.
这次又有什么事
What is it this time?
是我不好  我今天辞职了
Actually, It's kind of my fault. I quit today.
但工作重要
But work comes first!
你要辞职真可惜  出了什么事
But hey, that's sad about you, though. What happened?
出了什么事  精疲力尽了
What happened? Burn out?
精疲力尽了是吗
Burn all out, did you?
不是  他另谋高就去了
No. He's leaving for a better job.
太好了  我想那就再见了
That's great. So I guess this is goodbye then.
再见
Goodbye.
-好吧  -好的
- Okay, then. - Okay.
我们会想你的
Well, we're gonna miss you around here.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
-星期六见  -没问题
- So see you on Saturday. - Yeah, you bet!
知道吗  那是一种印度佳肴
Now, you know those are a delicacy in India.
是莱丝莉呼叫我  看我们能不能再合作
That was Leslie calling again to see if we can get back together.
她今天已经打了20次了
It's like the 20th time today.
祝你好运  莱丝莉
Yeah, good luck, Leslie.
她一定把你伤得很重
She must've hurt you pretty bad, huh?
是啊  我们曾是最好的朋友
Well, yeah. You know, we were best friends...
我们从小就是好朋友
ever since we were little.
我们的母亲是游艇上的同事
Our moms worked on the barge together.
你们两个在游艇上跑来跑去一定很可爱
You two must've been so cute, running around on a barge.
游艇上不能跑来跑去
You never run on a barge!
钱德勒在吗
Is Chandler around?
不在  他在咖啡馆认识了一个女的
No. He met some girl at the coffeehouse.
金吉儿什么的
Ginger something.
不是吧  不可能吧
No...  No, no.
你确定不是金吉儿的谐音吗
Are you sure it wasn't something that sounded liked Ginger?
比如说金洁儿
Like "Gingeer"?
不  是金吉儿
No, it was Ginger.
我之所以记得是因为他告诉我的时候  我说
I remember because when he told me, I said:
电影明星
The movie star.
老天
Oh, man!
我就是在躲这个女的
That's the girl I was hiding from.
要是知道他是我室友
When she finds out he's my roommate,
她一定会把我的丑事抖出来
she's gonna tell him what I did.
你做了什么
What did you do?
不  我不能...
Oh, no! I can't....
我不能跟你说
I can't tell you that.
我这辈子从没
It's like the most awful horrible thing
做过那么过分的事
I've ever done in my whole life.
别告诉我们
You know what, don't tell us.
等钱德勒回家再说
We'll just wait till Chandler gets home.
那样更好玩
Because it'll be more fun that way.
好吧
All right.
大概是四年前
Okay. It was, like, four years ago.
金吉儿和我约会了几次  有一个周末
Ginger and I gone out a few times. Then this one weekend...
我们去了她爸爸的度假木屋
we went up to her Dad's cabin...
只有我们两个人
just me, her and
还有她那讨人厌的小狗椒椒
her annoying little dog, Pepper.
那天晚上我做了一顿浪漫的烛光晚餐
Well, that night I cooked this really romantic dinner...
你害她食物中毒了
You gave her food poisoning!
但愿如此
I wish.
晚饭后  我们两个和椒椒在炉火前睡着了
After dinner, me, her and Pepper all fell asleep in front of the fire.
我半夜醒来时看到火快熄了
I woke up in the middle of the night and saw the fire was dying out...
就拿起一条木柴丢进去
so I picked up a log and threw it on.
至少我以为那是条木柴
Or at least what I thought was a log.
我的天  你把椒椒丢进火里了
Oh, my God! You threw Pepper on the fire!
但愿如此
I wish.
我应该告诉你们
See, I guess another thing I probably should've
金吉儿
told you about Ginger...
她其实
is that she kind of has a...
装了义肢
artificial leg.
我的天
Oh, my God!
乔伊  你把她的腿丢进火里后做了什么
Joey, what did you do after you threw her leg on the fire?
我逃跑了
I ran!
跟所有我在男厕所相遇的
That's the best kiss I've had...
其他人相比  这个吻是最棒的
with anybody I met in a men's room.
我也是
Actually, me too.
脚踩进水坑里了  全踩进去了
Foot in the puddle! Foot all in the puddle!
要命  我最讨厌这样
Damn! I hate that!
你得把鞋子脱掉
We're gonna have to get you out of those shoes.
不要紧的
Don't worry about it.
不  真的  你会冻坏的
No, really. You're gonna freeze.
我不会
No, I'm not.
你不会  你装了仿生脚吗
You're not? What you got a bionic foot?
也许有一天会吧
Someday. Maybe.
这本书很好笑吗
Funny book?
不  不好笑
Oh, no, no.
我只是在想我今天听到的一句很好笑的话
I'm just thinking about something funny I heard today.
马克说  "星期六见"
Mark saying, "I'll see you Saturday."
对  我们要去听讲座
Yeah, at the lecture.
我上星期就告诉你了  你说你不介意
I told you that last week. You said you didn't mind.
不不不  我不是介意那场讲座
Oh, no, no, no. It's not the lecture I mind.
拜托  不会是因为我要跟马克一起去吧
Please tell me it's not because I'm going with Mark.
-这个嘛  -我的天  罗斯
- Well... - Oh, my God! Ross!
对不起  不过你们已经不是同事了
I'm sorry, but, look if you're not working with him anymore...
为什么还要混在一起
why do you still have to do stuff with him?
因为他是我朋友
Because he's my friend.
但你真的还需要其他"朋友"吗
Okay. But do you really need another "friend"?
好吧  如果我不跟乔伊和钱德勒玩
Okay, well, if I stop playing with Joey and Chandler,
那可以跟马克玩吗
can I play with Mark?
这好笑吗  我应该笑吗
Is that funny? Am I suppose to be laughing?
我不知道  你觉得"星期六见"很好笑
I don't know. You thought "See you Saturday" was funny.
亲爱的  马克也是搞时装的
Honey, Mark is in fashion, okay?
我喜欢有个能说得上话的朋友
I like having a friend I can share this stuff with.
你们这些男生才不会跟我去听讲座
You guys would never go to a lecture with me.
我很愿意跟你去
I'd love to go with you.
真的
Really?
是啊  我有衣服
Yeah. I have clothes.
还是我自己挑的
I even pick them out.
告诉你  我可以当个时装
For all you know, I could be a fashion...
摊贩
monger.
好的  亲爱的  我很高兴你愿意陪我去
Okay, honey, I would love for you to go with me.
怎么了
What?
我该穿什么衣服  这下我好紧张
What should I wear? Now I'm all nervous.
人家说  "有人看的锅子不会叫"
You know, they say "A watched pot never beeps."
已经几个小时了
It's you know, been a couple hours...
她没有打来
and she hasn't called.
不是说我在乎  我不在乎
Not that I even care. I don't.
你干脆打电话给她吧
Why don't you just call her?
看你就知道你很想打
You obviously want to.
你自以为很了解我
You think you know me so well.
你不想打吗
Well, don't you wanna?
想
Yeah.
所以我的确很了解你
Okay. So I do know you.
我就是这个意思
That's what I said.
怎么样
Well, so?
我办不到
I can't.
我办不到  她抛弃了我
I can't. She dumped me.
我完全相信她  然后突然有一天
I totally trusted her, then one day it was like:
"再见  菲比"  一去不回
"Okay, bye, Pheebs." Gone!
你知道最叫人难过的是什么吗
You know what the saddest part is?
我们在一起表演的时候
When we were playing together, that was like...
是我这辈子最快乐的时光
the most fun I've ever had in like all my lives.
我最爱的鞋子真好穿  我每天非穿不可
My favorite shoes, so good to me I wear them every day.
鞋底塌了  脚趾开口  不在乎别人怎么说
Down at the heel, holes in the toes don't care what people say.
我双脚的知音
My feet's best friend pals to the end.
穿着它我就是性感小辣妹
With them, I'm one hot chickie.
不过有一天晚上天色灰暗
Though late one night not much light
我踩到了黏黏的东西
I stepped in something icky.
黏黏的鞋子  黏黏的鞋子
Sticky shoes, sticky shoes
永远让我破涕为笑
always make me smile.
黏黏的鞋子  黏黏的鞋子  下次我要
Sticky shoes, sticky shoes next time I'll...
躲开
avoid the...
烂泥巴
pile!
我们开始看到许多层的薄纱质料和颜色
We're getting to see a lot of layering of sheer fabrics and colors.
例如  薄纱的海军蓝衬衫搭配一件...
For instance, a sheer navy blouse over a pink....
我很高兴我们来听讲座
I'm really glad we came.
你好美
You're so pretty.
我爱你
I love you.
臭臭猫  臭臭猫
Smelly cat, smelly cat,
他们拿什么给你吃
what are they feeding you?
臭臭猫  臭臭猫
Smelly cat, smelly cat,
这不是你的错
it's not your fault.
-太棒了  -是吗
- That's great!- Oh yeah?
这首歌可以拿去卖
You know, you could totally sell this.
非常适合用来  促销猫砂
It'd be perfect for, like, a kitty-litter campaign.
广告歌  不行不行
A jingle? No, no, no.
有何不可  可以赚大钱
Why not? You'd make a ton of money.
我要是为了赚钱  早就成百万富翁了
If I was in this for the money, I'd be a millionaire by now.
你得把广告歌这种事给忘了  亲爱的
You gotta get out of that jingle-head, sweety.
你说得对  对不起
You're right. You're right. I'm sorry.
没关系
That's okay.
我现在要唱一首非常哀伤的歌
I'm gonna play a song now that's really, really sad.
叫做《魔术箱搞混了》
It's called "Magician Box Mix-Up."
特大号的手镯  特大号的耳环
Oversized bracelets, oversized earrings...
一般来说特大号的配件是今年的主流
oversizing of accessories, in general, is very popular now.
可以借我吗  我的牛奶坏了
Can I borrow this? My milk's gone bad.
我不喜欢这样
I hate that.
我以前很喜欢跟别人分着用  结果车被偷了
I once had a thing of half-and-half. Stole my car.
你跟金吉儿的约会怎么样了
So how was your date with Ginger?
太棒了
Great.
很棒  她
It was great. She's....
她很棒  长得漂亮性情好  无可挑剔
She's great. Great looking great personality. She's greatness.
看样子她很
Sounds like she's got the...
完整
whole package.
乔伊跟你说过那条腿的事了
Joey told you about the leg, huh?
老天  吓死我了
Oh, God! It freaked me out.
我知道不应该这样  但这是真的
Okay, I know it shouldn't have, but it did.
我喜欢她  想跟她交往下去
I like her, I don't wanna stop seeing her,
不过我总忍不住想问  "你的腿呢"
but every so often it's like: "Hey, you know what? Where's your leg?"
我是全世界最渺小的人  是吧
I mean, I'm the smallest person in the world, aren't I?
我是全世界最渺小的人
I'm the smallest person in the world.
早安
Morning.
其实他才是全世界最渺小的人
Actually, he's the smallest person in the world.
听过火烧腿的事了吧
Heard about the leg-burning, huh?
她提过
It came up.
我知道机会渺茫  可是
Listen, I know it's a long shot, but...
她觉得这件事好笑吗
by any chance, did she find that funny?
我只是打了一下瞌睡
So I nodded off a little!
打瞌睡  罗斯  你还打呼
"Nodded off"? Ross, you were snoring!
我爸的船撞上岩石  都没有这么大声
My father's boat didn't make that much noise when it hit rocks!
拜托  45分钟
Come on! Forty-five minutes....
那个人讲了45分钟的露背吊带裙
Forty-five minutes, the man talked about strappy-backed dresses.
那在冰冷的博物馆礼堂坐上四个小时
Okay, how about four hours in a freezing museum auditorium...
听皮兹坦教授说
listening to Professor "Pitstains" say:
大家好
"Hi, every body.
记得亿万年前死掉的东西吗
Remember that thing that's been died for a gazillion years ago?
我们过去不知道它有这块小骨头
Well, here's a little bone we didn't know it had!"
首先  他是皮坦教授
First of all, it's Professor Pitain.
其次  那块小骨头证明了
And second of all, that little bone proved that...
那只恐龙有翅膀  可是不会飞
that particular dinosaur had wings but didn't fly.
你知道我听到的是什么吗
Okay, you know what I just heard?
废话  废话  全是废话
Blah, Blah, Blah...
一亿人跑去看那部
You know what? A hundred million people went to
以我的工作为题材的电影
see a movie about what I do.
不知道会有多少人去看
I wonder how many people would go see a movie
叫做《侏罗纪风衣》的电影
called Jurassic Parka.
你实在是...
Oh, that is so...
一群抓狂的外套控制了整个小岛
A bunch of out-of-control jackets take over an island!
如果我的工作这么差劲
You know. If what I do is so lame...
那你今天早上为什么要坚持陪我去
then why did you insist on coming with me this morning?
这样我就不会跟马克去吗
Was it so I just wouldn't go with Mark?
不
No.
我想跟你在一起
I wanted to be with you.
我不知道  我最近觉得
I don't know, I feel like lately...
你离我越来越远
feel like you're slipping away from me...
你有了新工作  认识了新朋友
you know, with this new job and all these new people.
你的人生多姿多彩
And you've got this whole other life going on.
我知道这很傻
I know it's dumb...
但我痛恨不能参与你的生活
but I just hate that I'm not a part of it.
这并不傻
It's not dumb.
但也许你不参与也不要紧
But maybe it's okay that you're not a part of it.
你懂我的意思吗
You know what I mean?
我是说
I mean, it's like...
我不希望你参与我在这方面的生活
I like that you're not involved in that part of my life.
这样就清楚一点了
That's a little clearer.
亲爱的  这并不表示我不爱你
Honey, see, it doesn't mean that I don't love you...
因为我是爱你的  我非常爱你
because I do. I love you, I love you so much.
但是这是我的工作  你明白吗
But my work It's for me, you know?
我独立自主  努力投入
I'm out there on my own, and I'm doing it.
这很可怕
And it's scary,
但我很喜欢  因为这是属于我的
but I love it because it's mine.
这样可以吗
But I mean, is that okay?
当然
Sure.
你在想我的腿  是吧
You're thinking about my leg, aren't you.
不  其实我已经忘了  那是怎么回事
No, actually, I forgot. What's the deal with that again?
如果你介意也不要紧
It's okay if it bothers you.
我只需要知道你介意到什么程度
I mean the only thing I need to know it's how much it bothers you...
因为我不喜欢浪费时间
because I don't like wasting my time.
我在浪费时间吗
Am I wasting my time?
不  我想没有
No, I don't think so.
这也没什么  只要习惯就好了
It's just like anything else. You just have to get used to it.
那是什么
What's that?
那是我的"肉瘤"
That's my "nubbin."
肉瘤是什么
What's a nubbin?
就好像是第三个乳头
It's kind of a third-nipple kind of thing.
你有三个乳头
You have three nipples?
有两个正常的
Well, you know, two regulars...
还有一个算不上是
and one that barely qualifies as a...
怎么了
What?
没什么  我...
Nothing. You know, I...
我想起来了  我该走了
I just remembered. I have to leave.
你要走  现在吗  为什么
You have to leave? Now? How come?
肉瘤  没什么
Well, it's nubbin. Nothing!
这样吧  再联络
You know what? I'll see you later, okay?
我还以为你不来了
I thought you weren't coming.
-你到哪里去了  -过来吧
- Where were you? - Come here, come here.
不要生气  好吗
Okay, don't get mad, okay?
不要让我生气  好吗
Don't give me a reason to get mad, okay?
我把《臭臭猫》唱给旧广告公司听
I played Smelly Cat for the people in my old ad agency.
他们爱死了
They went nuts!
不  我说过我不要你拿去卖
No, look, I told you that I didn't want you to try and sell it...
你这个大肥猫还是做了
and you just you big, fat did it anyway!
我想五年前
You know what, I think, five years ago,
我恐怕会不计一切
I probably would have done anything...
只求能跟你一起表演
to play with you.
但我自己还是可以唱
But I can do it by myself.
如果我不能信任你  就散伙吧
If I can't trust you, then forget it.
不  我不想散伙
No, I don't wanna forget it.
这样吧  你必须做个选择
You know what? You have to choose.
如果你觉得世界上最重要的
All right? If the most important thing on the planet to you...
是猫拉屎之类的事情
is this cat-poopy thing, then okay,
那《臭臭猫》就送给你了
you can have Smelly Cat.
但我们以后再也不是搭档了
But we won't be partners.
你看着办吧
So what's it gonna be?
-臭臭猫  臭臭猫  -猫砂盒有臭味
- Smelly cat, smelly cat. - Problem odor in the litter box?
不要换猫  换猫砂就行
Don't change your kitty, change your kitty litter.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
太遗憾了  菲比
Sorry, Pheebs.
你没事吧
You okay?
我没事
I actually am.
因为生活中会遭遇各种事情
Because, you know, life's gonna hand you all kinds of stuff.
得到教训以后  希望可以成长
You learn your little lessons and hopefully you grow.
-要听新歌吗  -太好了
- You wanna hear a new song? - We'd love to.
广告婊子又来搞我
Jingle bitch screwed me over.
去死吧  广告婊子
Go to hell, jingle whore.
去死吧...
Go to hell, go to hell, go to hell.
我只写了这么多
That's all I have so far.
-你到哪里去了  -医院
- Where you been? - The doctor.
-你没事吧  -当然
- So is everything okay? - Oh, yes.
只是动了肉瘤切除术
Just had me a little nubbin-ectomy.
两个乳头  说做就做
Two nipples, no waiting.
跟瑞秋在高中的时候一样
Well! Just like Rachel in high school.
什么
What?
拜托  我是开玩笑的
Come on, I was kidding!
一听就知道是个笑话
It was such an obvious joke.
的确一听就是个笑话
That was an obvious joke.
可是我没听出来  为什么
And I didn't think of it. Why didn't I think of it?
我才华的来源
The source of all my powers.
老天  我都做了些什么
Oh, dear God, what have I done?